Rohan Samuel

Computer Science Student

www.rohansamuel.co.uk



www.github.com/RSAMUEL12

Contact Details

+447522482007

rohansamm@gmail.com 4 Larkspur Avenue, Healing, 🛖 Grimsby, DN41 7JD



A creatively-driven and people-oriented Computer Scientist with experience in project management through programming and societal projects, and in software development through effective and co-operative team projects.

Education

University of Warwick

Computer Science BSc

Oct 2018 - Jul 2021

Modules: Software Engineering, Project Management, Machine Learning, Visualisations, Algorithms, Database Systems

Caistor Grammar School

A-Levels and GCSE

Sept 2011 - Jul 2018

· Maths, Computer Science Physics: AAA

Experience

Digital Presence Member and Graphic Designer

Warwick Graphic Design and Marketing Society, Coventry Oct 2020 - Present

- Actively involved in brand campaigns such as the '12 Days of GDMS' to provide giveaways and gain publicity.
- Maintained the website using WordPress and Elementor Pro, and actively create pages for events like the Graphic Design course for marketing

Tech Team Member and Co-Technical Director

TEDx Warwick, Coventry

Oct 2019 - Present

- Collaborated with the creative and content teams to create speaker videos using video editing and production skills for both main events and interviews.
- Created, designed, and maintained the TEDxWarwick website using Wix and Corvid with Javascript, and took the initiative to create a Blog for the organisation.
- · Able to overcome the issue of no physical events with planning and set-up of a new virtual 2021 event by researching online platforms and creating video production kits for remote speaker recordings

Web Developer

Warwick Data Science Society, Coventry Oct 2019 - Jun 2020

- Created of the prototype website by utilising HTML, CSS and JavaScript programming alongside Google Scripts by creating a static page with mailing capabilities.
- · Performed marketing duties by sharing planned speaker events and workshops.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

Proficient: Python, Java, HTML, CSS Familiar: C, C++, Javascript, Prolog

Frameworks and Technologies

GitHub, SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB, Flask RESTful, UNIX, Windows Powershell, Jupyter Notebook, Bootstrap 4, React Native

Miscellaneous

Adobe Creative Cloud, Da Vinci Resolve, GSuite, Microsoft Office

Projects

Derivative Trading System

A trading system built from scratch as a group project to tackle the problem of fat-finger errors by using Machine Learning to find potential errors.

Built using: Python, Bootstrap, Javascript, SQL

Non-Linear ML Multi-Class Classification

A Multi-class Perceptron that classifies the Iris Dataset using PCA Decomposition, and utilises Kernel Latent Factor Models to improve accuracy of classification.

Built using: Python, Jupyter Notebook

Data Visualisations

- 1. An employee review visualisation using Glassdoor reviews to identify the best technology company to work for.
- 2. A Kinetic Theory of gases model to visually explain the effects of changing conditions.

Built using: Java, Processing (Software)

Compiler for PLM programming language

A parser and lexer that enforced the rules of a programming language called PLM, by checking syntax of written program code, and evaluating results from valid code.

Built using: Java, JavaCC

Interests and Achievements

- Graphic Design
- Photography
- UI Design
- DofE Gold Award
- · Bright Network Internship **Experience Technology**